Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - Men in suits, in front of a portrait of King Fuad (linked ref1153). 35.8 x 41.5 cm, Undated; cuid1128 (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Zagazig, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - Six men in suits pose in a garden. 32.8 x 44.0 cm, Undated; cuid1129 (Box 6, Folder 1, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Signatures; Buildings; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Gardens; Parks; Hats
  - A large group of men, with Egyptian flags in the background (linked ref1159). 33.3 x 39.9 cm, Circa 1923-1952; cuid1130 (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Flags; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing; Hats
  - A group of men pose outside a building. Arabic text on reverse: Mohamed Effendi Chadi (linked ref1158). 34.3 x 41.5 cm, 13 November 1934; cuid1131 (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Buildings; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Flags; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group of men outside an ornate building with Arabic calligraphy on it (linked ref1161). Arabic text on front: Abdul Majid Effendi Mohammad - Gift from his colleagues. 33.9 x 40.5 cm, 19 June 1938; cuid1132 (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Arabic Calligraphy; Hats
  - A group of men standing in front of a large building (linked ref1160). Arabic text on front: Abdul Majid Effendi Mohammad - Gift from his colleagues. Visit of General Prosecutor, Labib Beg Attiyya. Visit to city of Luxor, Egypt. 33.4 x 41.1 cm, 19 May 1935; cuid1133 (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Luxor, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats; Law; Canes/Walking Sticks
  - A group of men, some in military uniforms, in front of a building. 33.9 x 40.8 cm, Undated; cuid1134 (Box 6, Folder 2, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Group Portraits; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Boys; Children; Medals/Insignia; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - Twelve men in suits and tarbouches, outside a building lined with hedges. 34.0 x 40.8 cm, Undated; cuid1135 (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Buildings; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A man in military uniform posing with men wearing gallabeyas and turbans. 36.0 x 41.7 cm, Undated; cuid1136 (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Turbans; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Facial Hair
  - A group of men in suits posing in a garden. 35.8 x 39.5 cm, Undated; cuid1137 (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - Men in suits posing outside a building. Arabic text on front. "Jalal Beg Judge of Abnoub. On the occasion of his transfer to Assiout." 35.8 x 11.8 cm, December 1933; cuid1138 (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Asyut, Egypt; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - Former Egyptian President Gamal Abdel Nasser and large group of men and women. Arabic text on reverse: "Alexandria Safa Palace. Nasser Arab Representative - Conference" 33.7 x 43.5 cm, August 1966; cuid1139 (Box 6, Folder 3, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Alexandria, Egypt; Nasser, Gamal Abdel; Men; Political Leadership; Women; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Palaces; Facial Hair; Officials; Hats; Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1918-1970
  - A group of men outside a stone work building with two Pharaonic statues behind them. 34.0 x 40.9 cm, Undated; cuid1140 (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)
    Luxor, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures; Egypt; Buildings; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group of men posing in a garden. Arabic text on front. "Employees of the Accounting Department". 39.0 x 42.6 cm, 5 September 1929; cuid1141 (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Universities; Canes/Walking Sticks; Buildings; Group Portraits; Arabic Writing; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A group portrait of men wearing suits in Cairo University. 40.5 x 52.3 cm, 17 March 1927; cuid1142 (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Universities; Students; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Schools/Education; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A man wearing a galabeya and tarbouche. 35.7 x 29.1 cm, Undated; cuid1143 (Box 6, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Painted Backdrops; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Hats
  - A young woman wearing a dark cloak and hat, seated on a wooden table. 24.4 x 17.9 cm, Undated; cuid1144 (Box 6, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Women; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Hats; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Houses; Jewelry; Carpets/Rugs
  - A woman standing with her hand on her hip. 34.0 x 29.0 cm, Undated; cuid1145 (Box 6, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Cairo, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Jewelry
  - A woman wearing a black dress and ornate necklace. 36.0 x 29.4 cm, Undated; cuid1146 (Box 6, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Jewelry
  - A hand-painted portrait of a woman standing in front of a bed with a canopy. 37.5 x 27.5 x, Undated; cuid1147 (Box 6, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Houses; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Furnishings; Women; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Lanterns/Lamps; Paintings; Art
  - A man standing next to a table with flowers on it. 29.9 x 25.2 cm, Undated; cuid1148 (Box 6, Folder 6, Oversize unknown container)
    Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Men; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A man wearing a suit and tie. (Arabic text on front: "To the most respected, revered, beloved dear father, Sir I present my imaginary self as a gift. Mounir"). 27.5 x 21.2 cm, 24 December 1924; cuid1149 (Box 6, Folder 6, Oversize unknown container)
    Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Signatures; Arabic Writing; Men; Hats
  - A man in a suit and tarbouche with a cane. 27.4 x 21.8 cm, Undated; cuid1150 (Box 6, Folder 6, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Painted Backdrops; Asyut, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Hats
  - A man wearing a galabeya, bisht and tarboush. 15.6 x 11.6 cm, Undated; cuid1151 (Box 6, Folder 6, Oversize unknown container)
    Fez/Tarboush; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Regional/National Dress; Studio Photography; Hats
  - A man seated in a wicker chair, wearing a suit and tarbouche holding a magazine. 25.2 x 20.1 cm, Undated; cuid1152 (Box 6, Folder 6, Oversize unknown container)
    Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Men; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Hats
  - Three children posing around a wicker chair. Arabic text on reverse: "Cuba, from your brother Nasri, picture of my children, Joseph, Emily, Philip Terali." 13.5 x 8.8 cm, 21 June 1912; cuid1153 (Box 6, Folder 7, Oversize unknown container)
    Arabic Writing; Girls; Group Portraits; Boys; Postcards; Santiago, Cuba; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Children; Carpets/Rugs
  - A man in a pinstriped suit. Arabic text on front, "I'm presenting this picture of me to my brother's son as a souvenir, Nasri Terazi.". 28.0 x 17.9 cm, 22 September 1926; cuid1154 (Box 6, Folder 7, Oversize unknown container)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Men; Brooklyn, New York, USA; Facial Hair
  - A man wearing a tarbouche with a tassel and holding a cane. 16.4 x 10.9 cm, Undated; cuid1155 (Box 6, Folder 7, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Alexandria, Egypt; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Hats
  - A man in a mandarin collar jacket with military medals on his chest. 16.3 x 10.9 cm, Undated; cuid1156 (Box 6, Folder 7, Oversize unknown container)
    Albumen Prints; Medals/Insignia; Men; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A girl in a polka dot dress, with a pendant necklace, leaning on a table with flowers on it. 33.9 x 29.4 cm, Undated; cuid1157 (Box 6, Folder 7, Oversize unknown container)
    Jewelry; Girls; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Furnishings; Children
  - Mme. Eugene Grateyrolle in a light dress with a ruffled collar, profile with beads in her hair. 16.5 x 10.3 cm, Undated; cuid1158 (Box 6, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Jewelry; Tbilisi, Georgia; Cyrillic Script; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
  - A young man in a suit, with a short mustache. 38.0 x 26.9 cm, Undated; cuid1159 (Box 6, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Cairo, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A woman wearing a lace head cover seated on a velvet tuffted chair, holding prayer beads. Text on reverse: "Mme Kevork Bey Karakehya, mother of Abraham Pacha, Mme Foulik Nubar Pacha, Eram Bey, Meme Sultan Ohanes Bey Dadian, Melle Zarouhi". 16.2 x 10.6 cm, Undated; cuid1160 (Box 6, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; French Writing; Prayer Beads; Furnishings; Women; Egypt
  - A woman wearing a beaded dress, resting on a small table. 35.5 x 28.5 cm, Undated; cuid1161 (Box 6, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Jewelry; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Women; Egypt; Carpets/Rugs
  - A young woman in a long white dress with lace trimmings, leaning on a piano. 21.3 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid1162 (Box 6, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Pianos; Women; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Jewelry
  - A boy in a dark suit with a white armband, holding a large ceremonial candle with Christian iconography on it. 20.8 x 14.5 cm, Undated; cuid1163 (Box 6, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Children; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tuxedos; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Imagery; Boys
  - A woman wearing a pearl necklace and a dark colored dress. 34.0 x 29.2 cm, Undated; cuid1164 (Box 6, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Women; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt
  - A young man in a suit with a tarbouche and tassel. 19.9 x 16.0 cm, Undated; cuid1165 (Box 6, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Facial Hair; Hats
  - An elderly man wearing a light colored jacket and tarbouche. 24.0 x 16.8 cm, Undated; cuid1166 (Box 6, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Hats
  - A man wearing a three-piece suit and tarbouche with his hand on the back of a bench. 24.5 x 16.8 cm, Undated; cuid1167 (Box 6, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Men; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A woman in a sleeveless black dress leaning on a side table. 34.0 x 28.8 cm, Undated; cuid1168 (Box 6, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Women; Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography
  - A man wearing an agal and bisht. Arabic text "Al Haj Hassan Mhm Hassan". 23.2 x 17.3 cm, 1938 (1357 Hijri); cuid1169 (Box 6, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Facial Hair; Costumes; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Arabic Writing; Studio Photography
  - A man wearing a three-piece suit with a tarbouche and tassel with his hand in his pocket. 28.5 x 19.5 cm, 1924; cuid1170 (Box 6, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A man wearing a tweed suit. 21.7 x 16.4 cm, Circa 1926; cuid1171; El Hag Amin Mohammad Ismail, Rue Chekha Sabah Tantah (Tanta, Egypt) (Box 6, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; English Writing; Arabic Writing; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Hats
  - A woman wearing a long dark dress, holding a fan. 23.9 x 18.7 cm, Undated; cuid1172 (Box 6, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand Fans; Women; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Furnishings
  - A young lawyer, wearing a robe with a sash. 31.8 x 22.0 cm, 1 January 1930; cuid1173 (Box 6, Folder 11, Oversize unknown container)
    Law; Academic Dress; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Graduation Ceremony; Students; Books; Signatures; Men; Books; Fez/Tarboush; Carpets/Rugs; Medals/Insignia; Hats; Carpets/Rugs
  - A man in a suit and tarbouche, with a short mustache. Arabic text on front, "Riad Chehata, photographer for his royal highness". 32.3 x 21.9 cm, Undated; cuid1174 (Box 6, Folder 11, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Men; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A young woman wearing a watch and a dress with detailed sleeves. 32.3 x 24.5 cm, Undated; cuid1175 (Box 6, Folder 11, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Jewelry; Clocks/Watches; Furnishings
  - A boy with a book, leaning on a small table. 21.4 x 12.8 cm, September 1912; cuid1176 (Box 6, Folder 11, Oversize unknown container)
    Cairo, Egypt; Furnishings; Books; Children; Boys; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing
  - A woman in a white fur, with a cushion at her feet. 36.0 x 26.5 cm, Unknown; cuid1177 (Box 6, Folder 11, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Arabic Writing; Furnishings; Fur Garments; Women; Individual Portraits; Jewelry
  - A man in a suit with a handlebar mustache, holding prayer beads. 32.5 x 27.0 cm, Undated; cuid1178 (Box 6, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Facial Hair; Men; Facial Hair; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Prayer Beads; Studio Photography; Furnishings
  - King Fuad I of Egypt, wearing an ornate jacket and tarbouche, and holding a sword. 33.8 x 24.4 cm, Undated; cuid1179 (Box 6, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Men; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Gloves; Royalty; Hats; Fuad I, King of Egypt, 1868-1936
  - King Fuad I of Egypt, in a military jacket with a sword and medals. 40.0 x 23.6 cm, Undated; cuid1180 (Box 6, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Medals/Insignia; Military/Soldiers; Royalty; Weapons; Facial Hair; Fuad I, King of Egypt, 1868-1936
  - A man in military uniform, with a sword and gloves in his hand. 50.0 x 34.5 cm, Undated; cuid1181 (Box 6, Folder 12, Oversize unknown container)
    Medals/Insignia; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Weapons; Gloves; Facial Hair
  - A studio portrait of a man wearing a galabeya and turban with two other men in suits and tarbouches (same image as ref1348). 29.7 x 22.5 cm, Undated; cuid1184 (Box 6, Folder 13, Oversize unknown container)
    Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Turbans; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Arabic Writing; Regional/National Dress; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A portrait of a man and a woman, the woman wears an elaborately detailed dress and the man is wearing a three-piece suit. 24.0 x 17.5 cm, Undated; cuid1258 (Box 7, Folder 5, Oversize unknown container)
    Women; Men; Jewelry; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A group of nuns in white habits with a crucifix on a dark necklace. 19.8 x 28.4 cm, Undated; cuid1259 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Prayer Beads; Religious Crosses; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Imagery; Egypt; Prayer Beads; Women; Nuns
  - A Coptic priest in intricate robes and hat, holding a small ornate cross and a staff. 17.5 x 11.4 cm, Undated; cuid1260 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Religious Crosses; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Painted Backdrops; Religious Imagery; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair
  - A Coptic clergyman in black holding a cross and a bible. 17.2 x 12.0 cm, Undated; cuid1261 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Egypt; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Jewelry; Facial Hair; Priests/Clergymen; Books; Individual Portraits
  - A group of clergymen of varying ranks gathered around a man seated on a chair draped in a robe (linked ref1291). 8.0 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid1262 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Religious Crosses; Religious Imagery; Men; Religious Ceremony; Facial Hair; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - A group of clergymen of different ranks gathered around a kneeling man in black with their hands on his head (linked ref1290). 8.2 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid1263 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Religious Imagery; Egypt; Religious Ceremony; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Crosses; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
  - A Coptic clergyman holding a large staff in one hand with a group surrounding him. 8.2 x 13.1 cm, Undated; cuid1264 (Box 7, Folder 8, Oversize unknown container)
    Egypt; Men; Children; Religious Imagery; Religious Ceremony; Religious Crosses; Religious Crosses; Priests/Clergymen; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits
  - Group Portrait - Three nuns with schoolgirls in front of a building with wooden shutters (linked ref1294). 11.6 x 16.8 cm, 25 May 1924; cuid1265 (Box 7, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Schools/Education; Girls; Women; Nuns; Group Portraits; Students; Children; Carpets/Rugs
  - Group Portrait - Three seated clergymen with schoolboys in white uniforms (linked ref1293). 11.6 x 17.1 cm, 25 May 1924; cuid1266 (Box 7, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Group Portraits; Men; Children; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Boys; Schools/Education; Priests/Clergymen; Students; Religious Crosses; Egypt; Facial Hair
  - Group Portrait - Two nuns with schoolgirls in uniforms. 29.5 x 35.7 cm, Undated; cuid1267 (Box 7, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Schools/Education; Students; Uniforms; Religious Crosses; Girls; Nuns; Women; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Children
  - Sports Group Portrait - Bristol University Training College's football team, posing outside a stone building. 32.5 x 27.1 cm, Undated; cuid1268 (Box 7, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Men; Football; Sports; Football; Universities; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Bristol, England, UK; Buildings
  - Sports Group Portrait - Tanta Secondary School football team. 24.3 x 27.1 cm, 1913-1914; cuid1269 (Box 7, Folder 9, Oversize unknown container)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Sports; Boys; Football; Schools/Education; Men; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Football; Group Portraits; Children
  - The basketball team with teachers at the teachers' school. 28.5 x 25.5 cm, 1939; cuid1270 (Box 7, Folder 10, Oversize unknown container)
    Boys; Sports; Children; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Arabic Writing; Men; Facial Hair; Hats
  - A large group of men in suits, posing in front of a fabric backdrop, in a garden (linked ref1169 and ref1299). 34.0 x 41.9 cm, Undated; cuid1271 (Box 6, Folder 4, Oversize unknown container)